<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<group>
  <numeral>II</numeral>
  <stanza number="1">From that spot my spirit sprang in space -
My body's bulk abides. In dreams
My ghost has gone, by God's grace,
Adventuring where marvels have been.
I know no part of this new place,
I've come to where cliffs cleave the heaven.
Towards a forest I turned my face
And saw rich, splendid rocks that seem
Brighter than eyes on earth have seen -
The gleaming glory of every glint.
No garment made has ever been
Of half so dear adornment.</stanza>
  <stanza number="2">The valley's vista was adorned
With crystal cliffs so clear in hue
And bright woods by the hills had grown
With trunks as blue as Indian blue.
And burnished silver leaves all grind
And quiver together on every bough.
When gleams through glades upon them shine
Such shimmering shafts of sheer light show.
The gravel that grated on the ground
Was precious pearls of orient.
The sun itself is dark and blind
In respect of that adornment.</stanza>
  <stanza number="3">The adornment of that valley dear
Compelled my ghost to let its grief,
Freshest scents of fruit were there –
As if from food I was replete.
Fowls flying in the woods together
Were flaming hues, both small and great,
But citole-string or citherner
Their music's mirth could not repeat,
For when those birds their wings beat
They sang with such a sweet ascent,
Such gracious glee no man could meet
As here, or see their adornment.</stanza>
  <stanza number="4">All was adorned in dear device
In the forest where fortune made me fare
But to describe its gloriousness
No human tongue deserves to dare.
As a walked on in greater grace
No course or incline caused me care.
The further I went the fairer rose
The plain, the plants - the spices, the pears -
Hedges and meadows by river.
Gorgeous with gold the steep banks bent.
I went to the shore of the shining water -
Lord! It had a dear adornment.</stanza>
  <stanza number="5">The adornment of that darling deep
Was bonny banks of beryl bright.
Swinging sweetly the waters sweep,
With murmuring rondels, rippling straight.
Bright stones stood in the water's depth
Glinting through glass with glimmering light
That streams from stars while strivers sleep,
sparks in the sky on winter nights.
Each pebble in the pool was set
An emerald, sapphire or brilliant, 
So all the lake was set alight
With that dear adornment.</stanza>
</group>
